Drew Myers

Phone number: (419) 665-6133 Email address: drew@drewmyers.dev Website: drewmyers.dev

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/drewmyerslin/

Senior Software Engineer with 11 years of experience leading teams and building, testing and operating software on the frontend and backend. I enjoy working with interesting people and solving interesting problems. I'm comfortable leading, following and mentoring when called for. In my spare time I like to cook, read and tinker with things.

Work Experience

06/2020 – present Remote

Senior Software Engineer - Backend

- Lead a team developing a new backend infrastructure for customer visibility.
- Worked with customer and internal stakeholders to define Minimum Viable Product (MVP) and release that MVP to deliver customer value within six months.
- Managed roadmap to mature MVP into full-featured replacement for legacy visibility backend that can handle over 20 million events per day and retain them for years.
- Designed and implemented Elasticsearch indexing strategy to increase supported query parameters by 3x and decrease query latency for complex queries by >90% compared to NoSQL JSON store.

01/2019 – 06/2020 Columbus, United States

Senior Software Engineer - Frontend IBM

- Took over as team lead for a team of Junior frontend engineers struggling to maintain a complex React Single Page Application.
- Identified code quality and testing issues then planned and proposed a project to address those issues. Completed project on schedule.
- Increased test coverage from <10% to >90%, reduced reported bugs by >90%.

10/2016 – 01/2019 Columbus, United States

Software Engineer IBM

- Developed a customer config self-service application that reduced customer config change tickets by >90%.
- Worked with Architect to implement a resilient Kubernetes native architecture that won us an Outstanding Technical Achievement Award and became the reference architecture for other applications in our Business Unit adopting K8s.

06/2013 – 10/2016 Columbus, United States

Junior Software Engineer IBM

- Dockerized a legacy application, reducing startup time by 80% and reducing install time from several hours to instantaneous.
- Lead a small team of other Junior developers in creating new REST APIs for a legacy Java application that were critical in closing a >\$10M deal.

Education

09/2008 - 06/2013 Columbus, United States

Electrical and Computer Engineering | BE The Ohio State University

Skills

React, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Spring Boot, Kotlin, Java, Go, Python, Flask, Pandas, SQL, NoSQL, Elasticsearch, Kubernetes, Cloud, AWS, Testing, Debugging, Mentoring, Interviewing, Agile